# **CAROLE TIERNEY**

Software Engineer

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a software engineer with a former background on the AS400. My most recent experience was on an agile microservice team as a QA using Karate DSL for our test automation tool. Prior to this, I completed a Full Stack Developer boot camp where I created 3 personal websites and 2 websites collaborating with fellow students. I am looking forward to using these new skills in an entry level Front End or Full Stack position where I can apply my creativity while I hone in on my techniques.

### **CONTACT ME**

- **(**617) 775-0725
- Marshfield, MA 02050
- aroleatierney@gmail.com
- (in) linkedin.com/in/caroleatierney

#### **SKILLS**

HTML5 / CSS Node.js
Javascript Express
PostgreSQL PHP
MongoDB ReactJS
Git Karate DSL
jQuery Regex

### **EDUCATION**

SUNY Cortland 1988 - 1992
Bachelor of Arts in Math
Concentration in Computer Science

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2021 Minos Labs
Software Engineering Certification

2020 General Assembly Software Engineering Certification

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Quality Assurance Engineer, FIS** 

Remote, Jun 2021 - Dec 2022

- Worked on an Agile team incorporating SAFe with daily standup, two-week Sprints, Sprint Demos, weekly backlog refinement, system demos and a large planning sessions before each program increment.
- Created and executed Karate DSL automated test scenarios.
- Developed/maintained user stories in Rally.
- Debugged Java code and worked with developers to determine test failure causes.
- Used PGAdmin and Kafka UI to demonstrate team accomplishments in System Demos.
- Developed documentation for use by FIS coworkers on GitHub and team Wiki pages.
- Used Postman to test functionality of APIs.
- Developed Karate mock feature files to aid in testing API functionality.
- Used command line Git for version control.
- Worked extensively with JSON and relational databases.
- Monitored Jenkins pipeline builds and used OpenShift logs to determine failure points.
- Utilized Apache Kafka in our applications for event communication.

### Full Stack Software Engineer Student, Minos Labs

2021

- Participated in the Minos Labs Career Acceleration program: a 6-week, industry led cohort that gives associates with a STEM background the ability to advance both their technical and professional skills to that of someone with 2-3 years of practical, applied experience within Full-Stack Development.
- Developed a financial product using the Plaid API that integrated the frontend in React using Axios.

# Full Stack Software Engineer Student, General Assembly 2020

- Participated in a full time Software Engineering Immersive
   Program that included over 400 hours of training over 12 weeks.
- Learned and deployed Full Stack Engineering fundamentals such as accessing different APIs, full CRUD operations, the PERN stack, the MERN stack, algorithms and data structures.
- Built a portfolio demonstrating skills acquired.

# **CAROLE TIERNEY**

Software Engineer

## **CONTACT ME**

- (617) 775-0725
- Marshfield, MA 02050
- caroleatierney@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/caroleatierney

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

## Senior Software Engineer, Self Employed Aug 2002 – Feb 2016

- Designed, developed and tested software to support Business Intelligence, Marketing and Consultant Bonus programs.
- Provided quality assurance reporting to business users and produced systems documentation.

# Project Leader, PartyLite

Jul 1999 - Aug 2000

- Provided project leadership, business systems analysis and process improvements in business applications such as Order Entry, Inventory Management and Distribution.
- Worked closely with business users when analyzing and designing business process improvements.
- Implemented a new Warehouse Management System in Europe office.

### Senior Software Analyst, PartyLite

Nov 1997 – Jul 1999

- Designed and developed programs, systems documentation and related procedures to correct system problems, enhance system functions and support business processes such as the Order Entry System and the Warehouse Management System.
- Used SQL to generate reporting for Business Users.

### **Software Engineer, Accenture**

Oct 1994 – Aug 1996

- Worked on a Business Process Improvement team to customize programs to meet client's needs.
- Performed and documented unit testing.
- Developed systems documentation.
- Assisted in physical and cycle inventory processing.
- Modified and supported Retail System inventory modules.
- Provided on-call primary support on a rotating basis.